# Andrii Tsokur

## FRONTEND DEVELOPER

## SUMMARY

Skilled and creative **Frontend Developer**, with extensive commercial experience in the past, passionate about creating elegant coded, user-friendly, fast-loading web applications with semantic markup that enhance the user experience. In my person you will find reliable, punctual, goal-oriented, and friendly team member with a good sense of humor

## LATEST PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Phone Book (React, Redux Toolkit, JS, REST API, CRUD, AJAX, Webpack)
Code link | Role: Developer

Personal phone book allows you to add, search, delete and edit contacts (register or simply login as user0013@mail.com / user0013pwd)

Movies Database (React, JS, REST API, AJAX, NPM, Webpack)

Code link | Role: Developer

Online movies database (TMDB API)

Image Search Tool (React, JS, REST API, NPM libraries, Webpack)

Code link | Role: Developer

A tool for searching for images on the Internet (Pixabay API)

Mimino Recreation Complex (HTML, CSS, JS, Parcel)

Code link | Role: Developer

A team project. My contribution: development of the description sections in light colors on the main page and the entire restaurant page

Barbershop (HTML, SCSS, JS)

Code link | Role: Developer

Adaptive semantic landing page optimized for various devices

WebStudio (HTML, CSS, JS)
Code link | Role: Developer

Responsive and adaptive semantic markup for a concise website

Porten Wristwatch Retailer (HTML, SCSS, JS)

Code link | Role: Developer

Responsive and adaptive landing page with burger-menu

Picture Memory Game (HTML, CSS, JS)

Code link | Role: Developer

Designed to practice developing a JS-based logic unit algorithm

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Alcohol Export LLC | Jun 2021 - Present

**Achievements:** 9 new markets were contracted from scratch (Italy, Poland, Denmark, Sweden, Finland, Norway, Iceland, Faroe Islands, Greenland). This generated an additional 20% of turnover

#### SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

GT-Media Private Enterprise | Jul 1998 - Feb 2004

**Achievements:** In addition to my usual duties, I managed to contract Makoi LLC (USA) to carry out outsourced web development work in Ukraine for third-party US clients supplied by the company. This kept the company afloat despite the economic crisis that broke out in August 1998

## CONTACTS

- Odesa, Ukraine
- +380 (95) 089-2411
- tsokur@outlook.com
- www.tsokur.online
- Telegram
- Skype
- LinkedIn
- GitHub

## HARD SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, SASS / SCSS
- Adaptive / Responsive Layout
- JavaScript (ES6+) / ReactJS
- Redux / Redux Toolkit
- REST API / CRUD, SPA / MPA
- Parcel, Webpack
- Bootstrap, Material UI
- Git, GitHub
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, GTD

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Attention to details
- Effective communication & listening
- Goal-oriented
- Problem solving
- Team player
- Time management

## **LANGUAGES**

- Ukrainian (Native)
- Russian (Fluent)
- English (B2)
- Polish (A2)

### **EDUCATION**

IT SCHOOL GoIT

2022 – 2023

**Full Stack Developer** 

ODESA POLYTECHNIC NATIONAL UNIVERSITY

2001 - 2007

**MSc Economics & Management**